<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.13.30</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_30</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Invited Session IV: Extended reality--applications in vision science and beyond</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Invited Session IV: Extended reality--applications in vision science and beyond: Augmented reality systems for people with low vision</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Zhao</surname>
						<given-names>Yuhang</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>Department of Computer Sciences, University of Wisconsin-Madison</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>11</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>11</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>13</issue>
						<fpage>30</fpage>
						<lpage>30</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>Low vision is a visual impairment that falls short of blindness but cannot be corrected by eyeglasses or contact lenses. While current low vision aids (e.g., magnifier, CCTV) support basic vision enhancements, such as magnification and contrast enhancement, these enhancements often arbitrarily alter a user&#39;s full field of view without considering the user&#39;s context, such as their visual abilities, tasks, and environmental factors. As a result, these low vision aids are not sufficient or preferred by low vision users in many important tasks. Augmented reality (AR) technology presents a unique opportunity to enhance low vision people’s visual experience by automatically recognizing the surrounding environment and presenting tailored visual augmentations. In this talk, I will talk about how we design and build intelligent AR systems to support low vision people in visual tasks, such as a head-mounted AR system that presents visual cues to orient users’ attention in a visual search task, as well as a projection-based AR system that projects visual highlights on the stair edges to support safe stair navigation. I will conclude my talk by discussing our future research direction on AR for low vision accessibility.</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                
               <fn-group>
			<fn>
				<p>Funding: Funding: None</p>
			</fn>
		</fn-group>

	</back>
</article>