<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.13.25</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_25</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Contributed Session II</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Contributed Session II: Computational modeling of shift in unique yellow for small stimuli</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Rodriguez</surname>
						<given-names>Carlos</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Zhang</surname>
						<given-names>Ling-Qi</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Boehm</surname>
						<given-names>Alexandra E. </given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Greene</surname>
						<given-names>Maxwell J. </given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Tuten</surname>
						<given-names>William S. </given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Brainard</surname>
						<given-names>David H.</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>University of Pennsylvania</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff2">
					<label><sup>2</sup></label>
					<institution>Herbert Wertheim School of Optometry &amp Vision Science, University of California, Berkeley</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>11</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>11</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>13</issue>
						<fpage>25</fpage>
						<lpage>25</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>	Unique yellow (UY) is largely invariant to L:M cone proportion for spatially-extended stimuli in healthy trichromats. However, a recent adaptive-optics-based study by Boehm et al. reveals that when stimulus size is reduced to a few arcmin, color appearance depends on the local L:M proportion in the patch of the retina on which the stimulus was imaged. We aimed to determine if such findings are consistent with a normative account of visual processing. A series of 3.5 and 10 arcmin stimuli were simulated as isoluminant mixtures of 540 and 680 nm primaries. We modeled sensory encoding under adaptive-optics conditions using the open-source software ISETBio, for simulated retinal cone mosaics with varying local L:M proportions. The resultant cone excitations were decoded using a Bayesian image reconstruction algorithm (Zhang et al., 2022). For the 3.5 arcmin stimuli, as local L:M proportion decreased, the 540 nm component of the reconstructions increased relative to the 680 nm component. This is qualitatively consistent with the experimental observations of Boehm et al.  For 10 arcmin stimuli, in contrast, reconstructions were stable across variation in local L:M cone proportion. Notably, reconstructions depend not only on the local L:M cone proportion, but also on the proportion in the immediately surrounding retina, leading to a testable prediction. The computational observations frame the experimental results as a normative consequence of visual processing.</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                
               <fn-group>
			<fn>
				<p>Funding: Funding: The University of Pennsylvania Post-Baccalaureate Research Education Program, grant number R25 GM071745, and a research gift from Meta</p>
			</fn>
		</fn-group>

	</back>
</article>