<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.8.43</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_43</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Poster Session</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Poster Session: Estimation of crystalline lens mechanical properties from patient accommodation data</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>De La Hoz</surname>
						<given-names>Andres</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Martinez-Enriquez</surname>
						<given-names>Eduardo</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Marcos</surname>
						<given-names>Susana</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>3</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>Instituto de Óptica "Daza de Valdés", Consejo Superior de Investigaciones Científicas</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff2">
					<label><sup>2</sup></label>
					<institution>Instituto de Óptica "Daza de Valdés", Consejo Superior de Investigaciones Científicas</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff3">
					<label><sup>3</sup></label>
					<institution>Center for Visual Science, The Institute of Optics, Flaum Eye Institute</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>10</issue>
						<fpage>43</fpage>
						<lpage>43</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>Presbyopia is thought to involve changes in stiffness of the crystalline lens. Quantifying such changes poses challenges due to the nature of the lens’ materials. One approach has been to use finite element models and deformation profiles of lenses to estimate elastic moduli. In this work, this approach is extended to accommodation data for individual subjects. 11 subjects aged 20 to 30 were measured in an OCT system to record their accommodative response to a 4.5D stimulus. Lens surfaces were reconstructed from a diameter of 6mm and the periphery of the lens was estimated using eigenlenses method. The resulting profiles were used as input for a finite element model of accommodation. The lens was modelled with two primary components (nucleus and cortex) with elastic moduli for each region set as a variable. A load of 0.05-0.06N was used to approximate the accommodative process. An inverse modeling procedure was used to estimate cortical and nuclear moduli, by minimizing the difference between experimental and simulated surfaces at maximum deformed state. Estimated mean nuclear and cortical moduli values were 1.42 kPa (SD 1.16) and 7.07 kPa (SD 4.81). For all lenses evaluated, nuclear modulus was lower than cortical modulus. Age dependence was found for the average elastic modulus (R2 0.83) and for nuclear (R2 0.5) and cortical (R2 0.45) moduli. Results suggest that this method can be used to quantify stiffness of crystalline lens in subjects.</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                Funding: European project IMCUSTOMEYE H2020-ICT-2017 ref 779960,  European prject SIlkeye H2020-ERC-2018-ADG Ref 833106,  Spanish government grant PID2020-115191RB-100,  NIH grants P30,  Research to Prevent Blindness departmental funds to Flaum Eye Institute 
	</back>
</article>