<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.8.63</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_63</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Poster Session</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Poster Session: Extended Reality-based Minifying Lens Effects Decreases Dynamic Visual Acuity </article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Paladugu</surname>
						<given-names>Phani</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Waisberg</surname>
						<given-names>Ethan</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Ong</surname>
						<given-names>Joshua</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>3</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Zaman</surname>
						<given-names>Nasif</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>4</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Kamran</surname>
						<given-names>Sharif Amit</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>4</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Lee</surname>
						<given-names>Andrew G.</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5"><sup>5</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Tavakkoli</surname>
						<given-names>Alireza</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>4</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>Brigham and Women&#39;s Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA and Sidney Kimmel Medical College, Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff2">
					<label><sup>2</sup></label>
					<institution>University College Dublin School of Medicine, Belfield, Dublin, Ireland</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff3">
					<label><sup>3</sup></label>
					<institution>Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, United States</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff4">
					<label><sup>4</sup></label>
					<institution>Human-Machine Perception Laboratory, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Nevada, Reno, Reno, Nevada, United States</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff5">
					<label><sup>5</sup></label>
					<institution>Department of Ophthalmology, Blanton Eye Institute, Houston Methodist Hospital, Houston, Texas, United States + Center for Space Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, United States + The Houston Methodist Research Institute, Houston Methodist Hospital, Houston, Texas, United States + Departments of Ophthalmology, Neurology, and Neurosurgery, Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, New York, United States + Department of Ophthalmology, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas, United States + University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, United States + Texas A&ampM College of Medicine, Texas, United States + Department of Ophthalmology, The University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics, Iowa City, Iowa, United States</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>11</issue>
						<fpage>63</fpage>
						<lpage>63</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>
Dynamic visual acuity (DVA) refers to the ability to visualize objects in motion.  Gravitational (G)-transitions can occur during spaceflight inducing rapid sensorimotor adaptation, impaired DVA, and gaze control as observed in astronauts upon their return to Earth {1}. Previous research has used 0.5x lenses to simulate the decreased DVA experienced by a returning astronaut {2}. Minifying lenses cause visual inputs to move less than normal, which creates visual-vestibular conflict and can impair DVA. Our study reports the novel development and use of head-mounted, extended reality to simulate decreased DVA from G-transitions. We developed and tested this minifying lens effect with 5 healthy subjects (best correctable visual acuity of 20/20). The level of minimization was decreased in a stepwise manner from: normal, 30% smaller, 50% smaller, 70% smaller, 80% smaller. Measured DVAs were 0.485; 0.525; 0.695; 0.655; 0.855 LogMAR respectively, showing a decreased DVA as the level of minimization increased. There are currently no DVA assessment techniques in microgravity, which is why DVA and vestibular adaptations in space are poorly understood. Our group aims to address this crucial knowledge gap by developing a head-mounted visual assessment system that can measure DVA and highlight the potential of using extended reality-based minifying lenses to study vestibular dysfunction in both space and terrestrial settings {3}.</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                Funding: NASA Grant [80NSSC20K183]: A Non-intrusive Ocular Monitoring Framework to Model Ocular Structure and Functional Changes due to Long-term Spaceflight.
	</back>
</article>