<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.8.50</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_50</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Poster Session</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Poster Session: Deep retinal layer microvasculature alterations in first episode and chronic schizophrenia</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Fradkin</surname>
						<given-names>Samantha I.</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Bannai </surname>
						<given-names>Deepthi </given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Lizano </surname>
						<given-names>Paulo</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref>


					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>3</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Lai </surname>
						<given-names>Adriann</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>4</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Crosta</surname>
						<given-names>Christen </given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5"><sup>5</sup></xref>


				</contrib>



				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Silverstein </surname>
						<given-names>Steven M. </given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff6"><sup>6</sup></xref>


					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff7"><sup>7</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>Department of Psychology, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY, USA</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff2">
					<label><sup>2</sup></label>
					<institution>Department of Psychiatry, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff3">
					<label><sup>3</sup></label>
					<institution>Department of Psychiatry, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff4">
					<label><sup>4</sup></label>
					<institution>Maryland Psychiatric Research Center, University of Maryland, Baltimore, MD, USA</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff5">
					<label><sup>5</sup></label>
					<institution>Department of Cell Biology and Neuroscience, Rutgers University, Piscataway, NJ, USA</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff6">
					<label><sup>6</sup></label>
					<institution>Departments of Psychiatry, Neuroscience, & Ophthalmology, University of Rochester Medical Center, Rochester, NY, USA</institution>
				</aff>


				<aff id="aff7">
					<label><sup>7</sup></label>
					<institution>Center for Visual Science, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY, USA</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>7</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>7</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>8</issue>
						<fpage>50</fpage>
						<lpage>50</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>People with schizophrenia (SZ) demonstrate retinal microvasculature alterations that are similar to those observed in individuals with neurodegenerative disorders. Initial findings indicate that these changes are present in the superficial layer in SZ. This study examined whether changes are also present in the deep retinal layer level (DRL). Twenty-six individuals with SZ (10 with first episode psychosis [FEP]) and 37 healthy controls (HCs; 17 age-matched to FEP group) completed optical coherence tomography angiography scans. Compared to controls, people with SZ demonstrated reduced DRL perfusion density (ps &lt; 0.04) and vessel diameter (ps &lt; 0.01) in both eyes, and, in the left eye only, reduced vessel length and fractal dimension (ps = 0.01). We then tested for an illness progression effect by determining the degree to which the original 4 group means were characterized by a polynomial (linear) trend, using the following contrast coefficients: non-FEP SZ (-2), FEP (0), older controls (0), young controls (2). The hypothesized pattern was observed to a significant or trend level degree for 7 out of 8 variables, with effect sizes ranging from small to large. Findings also indicated that, within the SZ group, reduced DRL perfusion density and vessel length were associated with reductions in (previously reported) superficial layer indices (ps &lt; .001). Overall, findings suggest that alterations in retinal microvasculature are present in both the superficial and DRL in SZ.</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                Funding: Research reported was supported by the NEI of the NIH under Award Number T32EY007125. The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the NIH.
	</back>
</article>