<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.8.83</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_83</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Poster Session</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Poster Session: Peripheral blur may provide the eye with a cue for the sign of defocus</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Zheleznyak</surname>
						<given-names>Len</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>Clerio Vision, Inc.</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>11</issue>
						<fpage>83</fpage>
						<lpage>83</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>The sign of defocus is used by the retina to guide emmetropization. However, the means by which the eye determines whether light is focused in front of, or behind the retina, remains elusive. In the current study, we propose a new cue for the sign of defocus: the orientation of the anisotropic peripheral blur. Previously published [1] population averages of wavefront aberrations across the horizontal visual field in hyperopes, emmetropes and myopes were used to assess peripheral optical quality and blur orientation. Due to the large magnitudes of off-axis astigmatism and coma, the peripheral retinal image quality was dominated by anisotropic blur, whose direction was also correlated with refractive error (vertically elongated peripheral blur in myopic eyes and horizontally elongated peripheral blur in emmetropic and hyperopic eyes). The differences in groups may be due to the interaction between peripheral wavefront aberrations and globe shape (i.e. peripheral axial length). We also found an interaction between longitudinal chromatic aberration and off-axis astigmatism, wherein peripheral blur orientation is wavelength dependent, raising additional questions pertaining to the nature of chromatic cues. The orientation of peripheral blur may provide the retina with an optical cue for the sign of defocus, potentially playing an important role in emmetropization.
[1] Romashchenko et al., &#34;Peripheral refraction and higher order aberrations.&#34; Clin Exp Optom 103.1 (2020): 86-94.
</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                Funding: NSF STTR Phase I: NSF/IIP 1549700; NSF STTR Phase II: NSF/IIP 1738506
	</back>
</article>