<?xml version="1.0"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.0 20120330//EN" "http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.0/JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="Optica Fall Vision Meeting Abstract">
	<front>
		<journal-meta>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">jov</journal-id>
			<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JOVI</journal-id>
			<journal-title-group>
				<journal-title>Journal of Vision</journal-title>
			</journal-title-group>
			<issn pub-type="epub">1534-7362</issn>
			<publisher>
				<publisher-name>Association for Research in Vision and Ophthalmology</publisher-name>
			</publisher>
		</journal-meta>
		<article-meta>
			<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1167/jov.23.8.75</article-id>
			<article-id pub-id-type="manuscript">Talks_75</article-id>
			<article-categories>
				<subj-group subj-group-type="category">
					<subject>Poster Session</subject>
				</subj-group>
			</article-categories>
			<title-group>
				<article-title>Poster Session: Comparison of brightness and vividness of colors with different background colors in PCCS</article-title>
			</title-group>
			<contrib-group>
                          
				<contrib contrib-type="author">
					<name>
						<surname>Wakata</surname>
						<given-names>Tadayuki</given-names>
					</name>
                                        
					<xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref>


				</contrib>




                          
				<aff id="aff1">
					<label><sup>1</sup></label>
					<institution>Waseda University</institution>
				</aff>


			</contrib-group>
			<pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
			<pub-date pub-type="epub"><month>9</month>
				<year>2023</year>
			</pub-date>
						<volume>23</volume>
						<issue>11</issue>
						<fpage>75</fpage>
						<lpage>75</lpage>
			<permissions>
				<license license-type="cc-by-nc-nd" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
					<license-p>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License.</license-p>
				</license>
			</permissions>
			<abstract>
				<p>The purpose of this study was to compare the brightness and vividness of color on different-colored backgrounds. The stimuli were 173 patches of colors lying within the Practical Color Co-ordinate System (PCCS). The backgrounds were three achromatic colors: white, mid-gray, and black. Each color patch was pasted on mounts colored each of the background colors, making 519 combinations. Participants evaluated the stimuli on scales of bright to dark (brightness) and vivid to dull (vividness) using the Visual Analog Scale app on an iPad. They viewed the stimuli in a D65 standard light source booth in a dark room. The brightness and vividness scores for the three background colors were compared using Bonferroni correction for multiple comparisons for each color. It was found that, for both brightness and vividness scores, there were considerably smaller differences between a white and a black background than between a black and a gray background or a white and a gray background. Color bias was shown, with significant differences arising compared to the PCCS tone. Brightness and vividness evaluations were correlated; thus, they were integrated using Principal Component Analysis. The loading of the first principal component was 0.826, and this new integrated dimension was termed “Brilliantness.”</p>
			</abstract>
		</article-meta>
	</front>
	<back>
                Funding: None
	</back>
</article>